Hello, this is Siyuan Feng.
Today, I would like to talk about,
topic for the day, Trust But Verify:
Validating Data Masking Failure.
So first, a little bit
personal introduction.
as you know, my name is Siyuan Feng.
I'm a data analyst at a
legal service company.
I work on the test data
management, known as the TDM.
I get realistic data to the dev and
QA teams without leaking anything.
I later get reassigned, become the
QA for the software development.
I design and run the sensitive column
identification pipeline, which I'm
going to talk about for the day.
I'm also the author and the creator of the
DBmask, which is a open source database
masking tool under the MIT agreement.
So let's give an overview about what we
are going to have for the next 30 minutes.
first, why we want to mask our data.
What is masking?
Then third, how to decide
successful masking.
Step of the validation.
And then we have our quick topic
for the open source project.
And later, we will have
the final takeaway.
So first, we need to know that
why we want to mask the data.
Everyone need the test data.
Everyone just copy the production data.
Dev, quality assurance, and demo
team, they all need realistic data.
R-they need real format and real volume.
The fastest way to get it,
copy the production database.
Why?
Using a different volume and
the format between the dev and
prod will make bugs and errors.
For example, your code may only be
able to handle one hundred rows in
the dev, but you don't know that
if you can handle ten thousand
rows in the production environment.
So the direct copy is the most common
approach to prepare the test data.
And to give you a quick overview,
the database steward have
three type: dev, UAT, and prod
Okay, then we need to have
a quick overlook about their
advantage and disadvantage.
Well, first of all, test environment
don't have a good protection.
In the production database,
we have strict access control.
They have a lot of
monitoring and audit trail.
They have hardened parameter,
parameters such as MFA,
firewall, and strong password.
However, to do this,
everything come at a cost.
There will be much heavy financial
cost or labor cost to maintain
this level of the security.
On the other hand, the dev and UAT
has lot more, more se-- flexibility,
but it also come with cost at it give
broader access to devel- developer
and contractor, even the vendors.
It get weaker controls,
lighter or even no logging.
It has lower security requirement
by design, as I mentioned, just
to save the money, save the cost.
So in conclusion, same customer
data because they both, the
dev and UAT just a copy.
However, it's a weak protection.
In modern days, data leak can
cause serious damage financially,
operationally, or even reputationally
And you are going to ask next, "So
how should we enhance our protection?"
Well, by its name you
know it's the masking.
We have another example here.
We got a email, old email
called irate@old example.com.
Now it become after masking,
bahusk@newexample.com.
So as you can see, the format
re-retain its consistency.
Irate name become another name, bahusk.
email domain become email domain,
and there's a @ sign is still there.
We need to want-- We want to replace
the real value with a useful fake
and keep the consistent format
So raw data before and after masking.
Here we got a good example.
If you still don't have any idea
how the masking should looks like.
We have a column ma-ma-matter
ID, which is the key columns, and
we typically do not mask them.
We have the
contact email, which contain personal
email, which is a personal information.
reference number, note, which may
also contain the personal information.
As you can see here,
there is a phone number.
matter title.
Depend on the situation, because I work
for the legal firm, so, this title is
actually sensitive information as well.
Email template and intake channel.
These two are just the
categorized metadata information,
therefore non-sensitive.
And after the masking from
the source database to target
database, we can see contact.
Every email become masked
and become a new email.
Every reference number associated with the
customer become a new reference number.
Every notes, because there's no value
to mask them, we just blank them out.
They become blank value.
And the title for the legal case, they
all get masked in a similar format
And these last two column remain
the same So how do we want
to define successful masking?
Well, there are a few observations
from my previous slide.
As we can see, the quantity.
The quantity of the data
should stay the same.
It was, seven times five,
seven columns, five rows.
After masking it's still seven
point five, seven times five.
data format should stay the same.
Email address is still a email address.
Database elements should stay the same.
If there were the primary key
columns, then the primary key column
should stay as primary key column.
We want to make sure that data from each
row is actually masked, not skipped.
So each row, not just one
row, every row get masked
Three question before we deliver our data.
So first, we want to make
sure the row count match.
Do the number of the rows stay the
same from the source to the target?
Second, the element.
Does all the required element
object and the rule works?
Third, data masking validation.
Do all the sensitive values
change after the masking?
So there's two-- there's three step we
always need to keep in mind First, let's
talk about the role matching If we have
a table of the customer and orders,
before the masking there are 10,000.
Then after the matching,
there should still be 10,000.
Very straightforward and makes sense.
If the original data has 10,000,
then after masking it's still 10,000.
However, if original value is 30,000 and
you only got 29 and 800, then they are
missing 200 of the rows, which means there
are maybe 200 of the rows are mask fail
This is a masking failure situation
for our awareness, and it's
very straightforward And then we
should realize we should compare
every table, not just the total.
For example, here, if we compare
the total number of the tables,
then they actually stay the same.
However, if we look at each specific
table, then we will notice that
number is actually not matching.
Therefore, they have two
failure rather than none
We should also realize that
database element must match
We need to make sure that all the element,
such as the index, constraint, trigger,
grant, are all matching or stay the same
between the source and target database.
The consumer who consume-- the customer
who consume our masking data usually also
the devel-developer of the application
and the owner of the source data.
Their application may not be wrong
if it's missing, a index or grant or
constraint in their target database.
So first, let's look at the index.
in case you don't have the background
for the, SQL, index usually means
a shortcut to finding a record.
example here, we have a index using, this
number to find it in the masked emails.
if we have the index, then it will be
much faster to find the thing we want.
If we do not have the index, then
that means we need to do more
work, and it will slow us down.
So if you miss the index, it may still
be runnable or maybe it will be broken.
But, we are sure that it will
be much, much slower to run the
application, and it's bad for our
customer Next, we have the constraint.
basically a rule to
protect our entity's data.
For example, if we have a foreign key,
then it will restrict that our order
must refer to an existing customer.
In this case, if we're missing a
foreign key, such as the order, then
it will be not be, allowed to refer
that order number to a customer, which
means that our application will be
broken because it cannot associate
the order with a customer number
Next, we have the trigger.
The trigger is an
automatic database action.
For example, it will be automatically,
inserting an update to the order count.
So if there's a new orders,
the order count should be
automatically increased by one.
However, if we disable or delete
our trigger, then this throw-- this,
column will not be updated, which
means our application is more than
likely to be break And, that's a
better sense for our application.
Yes.
And, And then we have the grant.
Grant is basically the access control.
Example for this is, you know, I'm a QA,
so I only have access in a certain area.
I'm not supposed to have access as
much as developer does, because I'm not
supposed to change anything on their code.
However, if, our masking protection
somehow actually delete the grant or
disable the grant, then what we will have
is the QA can start modifying anything.
So if the QA just want to do some basic
tests, they end up delete the entire
code, then whose fault that's going to be?
In that case, they are gonna
be a disastrous situation for
the, for our data engineers.
But back to our topic, we should also keep
in mind that the grant should always stay
the same between the source and target
so that it can protect all the access.
Okay, so we talk about the, the element.
Now we are talking about
the most important one, the
data masking validation.
What if some rule is missing?
So, the reason for that is it can
happen when server run out of the
memory or when masking tool fail
to transfer, transform some of the
text with a special sign or foreign
language, and maybe other situation.
A quick example here is, so my name
is Siyuan, so this is my Chinese name.
But, as you can see, sometimes
our ETL tool may not be able
to read the foreign language.
So when they handling the foreign
language, it actually does not
to-- it not allow to process
the information, therefore, it
doesn't know how to replace it.
And then what we have is, we actually
stay the same between the source and
target because the tool cannot handle
that, and they just skip this entire row.
Which means in the end, we have
masking failure, and therefore,
we need to have a rule.
We have a tool, validation
tool, to capture that failure
And we should know that the data
validation will depend on the availability
of the keys In the first situation,
if we have the primary key in the
source tables, then that'll be easiest.
We just need to join the table
between the source and target.
The second situation is we can form
our own composite key when there's no
direct primary key available, but we
need to using some non-masking columns.
So there should be some non-masking
columns exist in order for us
to com- form a composite keys.
And last, which is the most
trickiest situation, there's no
way to form any kind of keys.
But don't worry, we got a way to cover
that Okay, let's start talk about the most
easiest situation With a stable primary
key, you can just match the same customer.
For example, we have the
primary key here, customer ID.
We just join the email
from the source and target.
We get customer 101.
In the source, it's iterate,
and the target is Bohus,
which means it get masked.
However, for the primary key
102, we got Npan at example.com,
and they stay the same, which
means our masking is failed.
The original email is
still on the same record.
It's very easy, straightforward to
detect this failure with the primary
key What if there's no primary keys?
Build our own composite keys.
We need to use stable unmasked
column whose combination is unique.
For example, here we can find a
stable pattern of the batch ID.
We can also find a stable
pattern of the record reference.
So both two number shows us a unique
pattern to form a distinct primary keys,
which is the composite key we have here.
So using these two column, we form
a composite keys, and now we have,
the source name can be joined
between the source, The name can
be joined between the source and
target using these composite keys.
And then we'll be able to see if any
of the name here is actually unmasked.
But please notice that finding and
building the composite key within
the huge tables can take times.
What if there's one hundreds
of unmasked columns that can be
used to form the composite keys?
If you want to list every combination
of the potential composite key,
it gonna take you hours and hours.
And make it worse, there are no
guarantee that you can find one.
You need to check every combination one by
one, which can be ten thousand or hundred
thousand for just one hundred column.
Okay, so what if there's
no usable key at all?
The most tricky situation, after you
check all the composite keys potential,
you still cannot find any primary keys
that can be found or built in the tables.
There's no way to join them
just to make the comparison.
First of all, this situation
can actually happen.
So believe it or not, some of the
legacy tables and migrants-- migration,
their key may not be available.
They may form a decade-old database when
there, when that times people do not use
the primary keys Log and duplicate record.
Sometimes the table, allow to duplicate
the structure on purpose just because
they need to pre- preserve every record.
All columns in the
table need to be masked.
For some of the small tables, area
of the column is actually sensitive,
so you need to mask off them.
And there's no way to con- construct
a composite key yourself The
solution for here is very simple.
We need to use the intersect
instead of the join.
When you use the intersect, you may
not be able to know which specific
rows is actually causing the failure.
But that's okay, because when you
run the intersect, you will know
which one is the overlapping values.
For example, here, we replace
all the password with randomly
generated string values.
So one two three ABC one one one AA.
So a password value to
a random string value.
In theory, there should be no overlapping
value between the source password
column and target password column.
Okay, I found this on the web
for there should be no value
between the crossword column.
Check it out.
We only need to intersect
these two password column to
find the failed masking value.
And in this case, the existence
of the overlapping value means
there is rows failed masking
So apologize for my theory.
and so for instance, this case, we can say
that after the intersection, we find the,
in this, the overlapping value is 123abc.
And, to know that which row is causing the
failure, we're just using the query set,
where the password equal to the 123abc,
and then we will be able to know, the
rest of the row number, row information.
So we know when this row equals 123abc,
we will be able to query that the
customer name equal to Super Bomb, and
then we will be able to identify which
row is actually causing the failure.
So if we are using the randomly
generated string value to do the
replacement, then there will be only
need to do a simple intersect, and
we will be able to solve this problem
Dictionary value can
overlap with source data.
This will be much, much more trickier
situation than the first one.
So still the same situation, we are
trying to check if there's any, data in
a table without primary keys, without
finding or building primary keys.
However, in this time, we are replacing
the old values, old value here, with
another value from our dictionary.
Simple val-- simple inter-intersection
here is not working or is not enough,
let's say, because the overlapping
value is legitimate to exist.
In this case, we use the
dictionary value to replace the
company name, as we just say.
And our dictionary may
already contain the name.
Dictionary is a dic- is a dictionary
tool that contain a list of
the, list of the value for you
when you want to replace them.
So in this case, I will
avoid the word in theory.
This can replace the Apple
with Oracle, which is good.
You can see the Apple
get replaced with Oracle.
This means that data get masked.
However, it may also replace the
Apple with another Apple here, which
is bad, and our masking is missed.
We just don't know which situation it is.
So the first situation, the Apple get
replaced with Oracle, which is good.
However, in the situat- second
situation, the Apple may stay in
Apple because there are another Apple
value still in the company name.
We don't know if it get real replaced
or it is just a failed masking The
solution for dictionary replacement.
Intersection is not good enough.
However, it can still be used.
Intersection is our first step.
We need to first find our
overlapping, overlapping values.
So in this case, we have the apple as
our overlapping val-- overlapping value.
Then check the remaining non-masking
column from source and target to make
sure that they are not the same So in
this case we had earlier, we had Apple
as our o-overlapping common value.
We should then check the rest
of the non-masking column.
Customer name is not masking here.
So we can see that for the Apple, as
overlapping values, the customer name
is actually different So in this case,
if they are not the same, in this
case, we get super pump warehouse bent.
It means there's no field masking.
To put into another ways, the
customer is actually changed and
their company name is also changed
So initially server farm get Apple.
Now, now if the server farm
Getting the apple.
And keep in mind, in this situation,
customer name is not get masked.
It's a non-sensitive value.
So as long as the initial non-masking
rule and its associated masking rule,
masking column does not stay the same,
then we can confirm that it get masked.
We're doing that by first do the
intersection and then checking
the non-sensitive column for that
over-overlapping, overlapping rules
To overcome and avoid suspense
So that's conclude our presentation.
But before we leave, then I
want to share my open source
project, which I called DBmask.
It's the same idea for everyone.
You want to discover, mask all sensitive
data in any database, open source for
everyone, and will also give you the
validation result once you finish that.
It's a clean room rebuild, no
company code, no proprietary rules.
Any Excel, SQL database, SQL
economy, PostgreSQL, MySQL,
SQL Servers, Python 3.9.
You need a YAML file to configure that.
MIT license.
Currently under version 0.1.1.
It's an initial framework, so any
contribution will be very welcome
And, speak of which, I have a, a quick
validation report for you to show.
So like I said, this open source
project include both the masking and
the identification of the masking, the
masking itself, and the validation report.
So once it finished masking
for you, it can automatically
generate a validation report.
So everything I cover in this, topic
today, it will be automatically done
for you, so you don't have to do
your own validation step by step.
So you can see here we got the row
count, source and target are matching.
Element check, index, source
and target matching all pass.
And the masking completeness, we
have all the sensitive value checked.
required rows, they all got ve-
verified, and they all got passed.
So overall result, it passed.
It's very simple and easy to review.
And if you are interested, please give
a thumb up on my open source project.
A star, please.
And, thank you.
That conclude my presentation for the day.
if you have any question,
please feel free to reach out
to me, at saionseacat@gmail.com.
And, here is my, repository code.
Thank you.